Welcome back.
And this lesson, we shall give an overview of the clock configuration tab.
It's over here.
We use this type of right here to figure out a system clock.
So based on what board you selected during the board selection, if you selected the nuclear board or
the disco board, the default setting will be different.
Right over here, the default is nine to six megahertz.
This the nuclear broad, it's nine to six mega heads.
And the maximum can be one hundred megahertz.
If you have the disco body could.
The default is 16 megahertz.
If you have a different version of the F4 microcontroller, you could have a different value here.
But in any case, it's always indicates the, um, the maximum down here.
So unless I want to said this to the maximum, I can simply type one hundred and hit enter over here
like this and is going to search for the solution because he has to update all the various parts in
order to be able to work with this frequency.
So it's been able to find a configuration out, provide me with its Yoki of 100.
And by doing that, it's adjusted the frequencies here as well.
Right.
So any one of that and you can see it, there are parts that are great out, this party is great out.
And if you want to know what the great out part belongs to, you, just put your point out there.
You will receive the info.
This is for the eye, too, as cloak.
And it's not it's not set.
So if we go to our pin out and enable the eye to us, then we expect this part to be enabled.
Let's check out and see.
I'll come back to pin out and then I'll come to multimedia.
So I'll see eye to us.
And then word I'll just select.
Healthmaster duplex.
Right.
Once that is done, I'll go to Kolok Conflagration.
And because I change something now, the clock on immigration has a conflict.
So it's asks, do you want to run automatic clock issues solver?
I can click, yes.
And then you will solve the issues for me.
So, yes, I cannot find a solution.
OK, so the reason I cannot find a solution is I would have to.
Just some of the settings here, which can be done from the.
These cities as well.
Right.
So, OK, what I wanted to show you is that this pilot was disabled.
Known that we've been unable to pay for that requires this plot.
We can see that this part of the clock is enabled robot here.
This this multiplex belongs to the RTC, the real time clock.
So it because we're not using the real time clock in our project, we see that it is disabled as well.
Right over here.
This one belongs to this one says MCE oh to source UKCS.
If we want to get more information about it, we can just drop all modes.
And when I put my mouse here, it keeps me information as to how to enable this.
It says MCO output is not available to enable it.
One of the following RACC modes or IP moves need to be set.
Right?
So because we know using this part, that is why it is great out as well as this part.
We can also adjust the clock off the various passes.
So if we want to adjust the clock for the APB to time up, it may be two bros four times, meaning all
the time is connected to EPB two.
If you want to adjust the crop for them, you can simply type here.
So let's say I type 50 megahertz.
Because I want to set a plan B, two is two.
This is gonna find a solution that works and by itself it would adjust the for me.
I can do it for all of these over here.
And one other thing whereby here we have high speed internal or neighborhood.
That is why we have this year because of a high speed extend or is disabled.
We don't have the option to select this.
So let's see how to enable high speed extend or I'll come back to a PIN configuration over here.
Come to System four and then RACC and then high speed, high speed quelque HFC.
I'll see.
Ceramic crystal or resonator?
And this this one here.
The nuclear board hasn't got.
The nuclear board hasn't got a ceramic crystal.
So this won't be required for a new clue.
But if you have that described as a ceramic resonator on the body, reason why Cube makes it allows
us to make this option is that the idea is you buy this microcontroller and order to a project.
And if I and it's your project, you add your own ceramic resonator.
It's not going to be a dev board.
This is for you in.
You know, production.
Great solutions.
So anyway, I've enabled this.
Let's go to the clock and see.
So Nundah often neighborhood.
I can choose HSC as my clock source.
Now I have the option to select both of them.
Right.
So there's a very quick overview of the clock configuration.
There isn't much here.
We just use it to adjust our clock as well as the peripheral clocks.
That's all you need to know with us.
Well, if we have any more information regarding the configuration of clock for a particular peripheral,
we'll talk more when we get it.
So that's it.
I'll show you the next lesson.